Michael Takeuchi

Phoenix, AZ 85016 | 310-256-8272 | mikemtaki@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Blog</u> |

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Web developer with knowledge in Ruby and Javascript languages, and background in sales, I bring strong communication skills, from collaborating with teams and clients. I have experience prioritizing tasks from working with changing deadlines and KPIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, SQL, Javascript, and React

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Boon - Github | Demo

Stock tracker to record stock transactions, and view total returns and market value of portfolio.

- Developed full Ruby on Rails web app, using Materialize framework for styling.
- Utilized Devise gem and Omniauth for user authentication, with the ability to sign in with a Google account.
- Programmed portfolio to showcase individuals profits and equity, along with the categories they
 are invested in.

Apricus - Github | Demo

Wine journal to document wine profiles.

- Designed Rails API backend with wine and reviews model.
- Implemented Javascript frontend and used Bootstrap framework for styling.
- Developed search filter to give users access to view only select wines by name.

EXPERIENCE

Southern Glazer's Wine & Spirits

Torrance, CA

Chain Sales Merchandiser

05/2016 - 03/2020

- Sold in monthly planner products for 24 consecutive months from 2018-2020.
- Built displays in 50% of accounts that helped buyers reduce inventory by 20% and increased sales over 30% YoY, during Q4 in 2018.
- Helped 5 new accounts organize wine and liquor department plans during grand openings.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

05/2020 - 10/2020

University of California, Davis Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Economics Davis, CA

06/2015